charity-commission.gov.uk 2011-11-25

# Copyright statement

#### Copyright Statement - © Crown copyright 2011 

The material featured on this site is subject to Crown copyright protection unless otherwise indicated. The Crown copyright protected material (other than the Register of Charities, the Royal Arms or departmental logos) may be reproduced free of charge in any format or medium provided it is reproduced accurately and not used in a misleading context. 

Where any of the Crown copyright items on this site are being republished or copied to others, the source of the material must be identified and the copyright status acknowledged. The permission to reproduce Crown protected material does not extend to any material on this site which is identified as being the copyright of a third party. Authorisation to reproduce such material must be obtained from the copyright holders concerned. The Charity Commission encourages users to establish hypertext links to this site. 

The departmental logos are registered as Trademarks. Authority for their use should be obtained from us. Enquiries should be made [via email](mailto:enquiries@charitycommission.gov.uk?subject=Request%20to%20use%20logo "Send an email"). 

###### Database right statement for the Register of Charities 

Crown database right 2001. The Central Register of Charities ("The Register") is subject to Crown database right. 

**You may:**

1\. access the Register and download insubstantial extracts from it onto electronic, magnetic, optical or similar storage media. The repeated and systematic downloading of insubstantial parts of the contents of the Register may amount to the downloading of a substantial part of those contents; 

2\. download the contents of the Register for the purpose of illustration for teaching or research, providing there is no commercial purpose; 

3\. download all or a substantial part of the contents of the Register containing factual information of any description for any purpose which does not involve making all or a substantial part of those contents available to the public by any means. 

These are the permitted uses. Any other proposed use of the Register and its contents would require a licence. The Director of the Office of Public Sector Information (OPSI) in their role as Queen's Printer has been appointed by Her Majesty the Queen to manage all copyrights owned by the Crown on Her Majesty's behalf. You can apply for a licence to: 

OPSI Information Policy Team   
The National Archives   
Kew   
Richmond   
Surrey TW9 4DU   
Email:[ psi@nationalarchives.gsi.gov.uk](mailto:psi@nationalarchives.gsi.gov.uk)

The Commission has a statutory obligation to permit the inspection by any member of the public of the information entered on the Register, and to provide, on request, and on payment of any prescribed charge, copies of entries on the Register. The Commission also has a statutory obligation to permit such inspection of the accounts and reports which are sent to it, and of the trusts of charities which are entered on the register. Again, it has to provide copies on request, and on payment of any prescribed charge. 

The Commission is not in a position to control the use which people make of information which it is legally required to provide to them. 

###### Acceptable use of Charity Commission Searchable Databases 

The Charity Commission searchable databases are designed to meet the needs of a wide range of users wishing to interrogate our information on-line. 

Due to limitations of equipment and bandwidth, they are not intended to be a source for bulk downloads. Although downloading all or a substantial part of the contents of the register for a purpose which does not involve making the contents available to the public would not be an infringement of Crown database right, it does cause heavy demands upon the system. Persons wishing to obtain an electronic copy of the whole register or a substantial part of it should follow the Commission's procedure for obtaining an electronic copy. 

Individuals, companies, IP addresses or blocks of IP addresses who generate unusually high numbers of daily database accesses, whether generated manually or in an automated fashion, may be denied access to these services without notice. In such cases they should follow the Commission's procedure for obtaining an electronic copy. 

Top of page

* * *

#### Disclaimer 

We have tried to ensure that all information we provide through this web site is correct at the time we included it. We apologise for any errors. We therefore do not guarantee the accuracy of these pages and any visitor using information contained in them does so entirely at their own risk. 

Top of page

* * *

#### Privacy Policy 

This explains how www.charitycommission.gov.uk, uses any information you give to us via our website, and the ways in which we protect your privacy. (NB It is not intended to be a privacy statement in relation to information submitted to the Commission by any other means.) 

###### The Data Protection Act 1998 

The Charity Commission is a Data Controller under the Data Protection Act 1998. We hold information for the purposes of maintaining the Register of Charities and certain other statutory functions as assigned by Parliament. The Commission complies with the data protection principles set out in the Data Protection Act 1998 in relation to personal data which you give to us via our website to the extent that the Act requires it to do so. These principles restrict the powers of a data controller to disclose to third parties personal data which it is processing. 

###### What information do we collect via the website? 

We collect four main types of information from visitors to www.charitycommission.gov.uk: 

  * feedback (general questions and specific feedback on the website);
  * notification of changes to entries on the Charity Commission’s Register of Charities;
  * representations on Schemes and Orders; and
  * site usage information (from session cookies and log files).

###### 1\. Feedback, questions and comments 

You can send us your comments to our email feedback address or from our website questionnaire.If you send an email or letter to us or call us for information, once we have replied to you, we keep a record of your messages for three months for reference and audit purposes, after which it is deleted. 

###### 2\. Representations on Schemes 

You can make comments or representations about a scheme that the Commission is making for a charity by email. A form is available for this purpose. We must take into consideration any representations that we receive within the statutory period of notice. We may decide as a result that the proposals need to be changed. 

We will retain a hard copy of your representation. This will be dealt with in accordance with the Commission’s record retention policy.

###### 3\. Notification of changes to entries on the Charity Commission’s Register of Charities 

Email requests to update or correct details displayed on the online Register of Charities are generally dealt with by our Charity Database division. The types of changes they deal with include changes to correspondent and website or e-mail contact details for a charity. The division also deals with amendment of charity financial details, area of operation, classifications etc. 

Anything that could indicate a change to the operation of the charity (affecting its governing document, name, objects, area of benefit etc) is forwarded to our Register Maintenance division for them to consider. 

All e-mails requiring our action are printed off and a hard copy is retained on the division for internal audit purposes. These are held for 6 months and then destroyed. This is slightly longer than the official retention period of three months for Register Check forms (which updates similar details). E-mails are deleted once the item is actioned. 

We will confirm that the requested changes have been made if you specifically request us to do so. 

#### 4\. Site usage information 

###### Cookies 

We will be unable to display certain pages such as the Welsh version of our site and other accessibility options if your browser is set up to refuse our cookies. 

###### What are Cookies? 

Cookies are small text files that are often created when you visit a website, and which are stored in the cookie directory of your computer. The cookies contain small pieces of data which are used on our website to store your current choices such as language and accessibility options . By reading the data in the cookie we are able to apply your preferences from page to page as you move through our site. The cookies our site uses are called "session cookies", which means that your choices, such as the Welsh language version and your preferred accessibility choices are stored temporarily while you move around the site. 

The cookies do not contain any personal information about you, and they cannot be used to identify an individual user. You can set your computer not to accept cookies but, if you do, you will not be able to use some facilities on the website. Session cookies are deleted when you exit from the Internet. They do not contain any personal information about you, and do not hold any information about which sites you visited before the Charity Commission website. 

More information on cookies is available from Directgov: 

  * [_Internet browser cookies - what they are and how to manage them_](http://www.direct.gov.uk/managingcookies "Internet browser cookies - what they are an how to manage them on the DirectGov website") (opens new window)

###### Log files 

Log files allow us to record visitors' use of the site. Specialist software puts together log file information from all our visitors, which we use to make changes to the layout of the site and to the information in it, based on the way that visitors move around it. Log files do not contain any personal information. 

We use Google analytics to manage log file information. 

  * [Read Google's privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy.html "Googles privacy policy") (opens new window)

#### What happens when I link to another site? 

www.charitycommission.gov.uk contains links to other websites, both those of government departments and of other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our site, so you should always be aware when you are moving to another site and read the privacy statement of any site which collects personal information. 

We do not pass on any personal information you have given us to any other site. 

Top of page
